索恩教授∶我们去年的戏剧表演非常的成功.
Professor Thorn: So, we have reached that magical time,
而现在,大家从蓝登毕业后,
the last drama project of the year.
你们当中有很多人会继续在百老汇,
Now, upon graduation from Landen,
电视和电影上追求自己的戏剧梦想;或者你愿意的话,你也可以去做一个侍者.
many of you will go on to pursue your theatre dreams in Broadway, television,
今天晚上的场面,
the cinema; or if you're really serious by becoming a waiter.
对你们所有的人来说,
This night of scenes is an important opportunity for all of you to,
都是一个不错的表现自己在表演上的才能的机会,或者是能让大家开启崭新的演艺事业.
as we say in show business, suck up.
因为很多我的来自纽约的重量级剧院的朋友都会来观看这场演出,
Many of my New York heavy-weight theatre friends will be in attendance,
所以,今天晚上的演出重要的不是最后的成绩,
so there's a lot more riding on this evening than just a good grade...
而是你们的将来.
possibly a future.
(在迈克的想象中)
(In Mike's imagination)
索恩教授∶我还能说什么呢,他会演戏,会导演,他就是戏剧...迈克尔西维尔.
Professor Thorn: What can I say, he acts, he directs, he is theatre...Michael Seaver
迈克∶嘿嘿,我经常都认为我自己还不错,
Mike: Well I always thought I was kind of good,
但是不知道会是这么的优秀.
but I didn't know I was this good.
凯特,你怎么穿成这样?
Kate, well what are you doing here dressed like that?
凯特∶你告诉过我,这是你的梦想.
Kate: It's your dream, you tell me.
索恩教授∶因此2星期以后,我们会展示给你看...
Professor Thorn: And so after two weeks, we will show it to you...
凯特∶迈克,不要再笑了.
Kate: Mike, stop smiling.
迈克∶哦,对不起,
Mike: Oh, sorry, right, I was day dreaming about what could happen...
我刚才正在做白日梦呢,想想会发生什么事...也在想你会穿什么..
and what you'd be wearing when it did.
(杰森和麦琪在玩篮球)
(Jason and Maggie are playing basketball)
麦琪∶太好了,进!哈哈,我又投进了.可惜的是,不是比赛!
Maggie: Alright...ooh...and in!And she scores again.It's not even a contest!
杰森∶是,是.把所有的力气都花在这里了,等我们一上楼就...
Jason: Yep, yep, yep.All in energy in the world out here, and when we
get upstairs...zippo
麦琪∶你说什么?
Maggie: Pardon me?
杰森∶没什么,宝贝.
Jason: Nothing sweetheart.
麦琪∶比分是多少了?我不记得了.
Maggie: Oh, what was that score?I forgot.
杰森∶比分...最重要的是,
Jason: The score...what's the point...
是我们俩都得到了锻炼,不是吗?
The point is for us to get a little exercise, isn't it?
麦琪∶噢呼,这就是你为什么会输的原因.明明比我还小13个月,居然这么不经打.
Maggie: Uh hu, that's why you are losing.Thirteen months younger and he folds like
a tent
凯特∶你作弊!
Kate: You cheated!
迈克∶我可没有.
Mike: I did not.
凯特∶让我看看硬币.
Kate: Let me see the coin.
迈克∶嘿,我赢得光明正大的.
Mike: Hey, look, I won the toss fair and square...
杰森∶还记不记得我们过去经常用猜硬币来决定什么?
Jason: Remember what you and I used to flip coins over?
麦琪∶我怎么会忘记呢!你总是选正面.
Maggie: Oh, do I!You always called pence.
麦琪∶现在还是一样.
Jason: I still do.
迈克∶凯特,你就是输不起..
Mike: Look Kate, you're just being a sore loser
凯特∶哦!是的!
Kate: Oh, yeah!
迈克∶公平就是公平,凯特!
Mike: Fair is fair, Kate!
凯特∶公平就是公平,凯特!公平就是公平,凯特!
Kate: Fair is fair, Kate!Fair is fair, Kate!
杰森∶迈克,迈克,
Jason: Mike, Mike, you don't even try to explain when they're in a mood
当她们不讲理的时候,不要想着去解释.
like that.
麦琪∶她们!
Maggie: They!
杰森∶不是指你,亲爱的.我说的是年轻的女人们.
Jason: Not you honey.I'm talking about young women.
不,我是说没有...的女人们.
No, I meant women without...
麦琪∶你真的想说完这句话?
Maggie: Do you really wanna finish this sentence?
杰森∶不想.
Jason: Na.
麦琪∶迈克,是什么事情?
Maggie: OK, what's the deal, Mike?
迈克∶哦,不必担心.
Mike: Oh, don't worry guys.It was just a professional disagreement.
只是一个专业上的分歧.
I mean, see, Kate and I are both directing scenes for drama class,
凯特和我都在为戏剧班导演戏剧,而我们俩却都看中了同一个女演员.
and we both want the same actress.
杰森∶哦,凯特在吃醋,哈?
Jason: Oh, Kate's jealous, huh?
迈克∶不是的,爸爸.
Mike: No Dad, I told you, this is professional.
我说过了,是专业方面的.你难道不知道现代的女人吗?
Don't you know anything about modern women?
杰森∶恩....
Jason: Well...
麦琪∶不,他不了解.那个女演员很特别吗?
Maggie: No he doesn't.What's so special about this actress?
迈克:你看,她在演连续剧,
Mike: Well, see, she's done sit-coms, and she's done real plays.
她是真正的表演.
Oh and Dad, OK, you know that commercial,
爸爸,你知道那个黑猩猩与女孩的喜剧.
with the girl and chimpanzee and they shave her legs?
杰森∶是的.
Jason: Yes.
迈克∶她在蓝登上课.
Mike: Yes.She takes classes at Landen.
杰森∶黑猩猩还是女演员?
Jason: The chimp or the actress?
迈克∶当然是女演员!在那些重要的纽约戏剧人的面前,
Mike: The actress!See,
我可不想把自己的首场演出搞砸.我是说当我去为他们效劳的时候,
I don't want to blow my shot in front of these important New York theatre
我要他们记得我是一个会演戏,
people.I mean when I come to work for them,
会导演,以及戏剧的男人.
I want them to remember me as the guy who acts, who directs, who is theatre.
麦琪∶你把所有的一切都押在一个硬币的筋斗上!
Maggie: You risked all this on the flip of a coin!
迈克∶什么风险?我所用的硬币2面都是人头.
Mike: What risk?I used a two headed coin.
麦琪∶迈克,你从哪里得到的一个2面都是人头的硬币?
Maggie: Mike, where did you get a two headed coin.
迈克∶从爸爸那借来的.
Mike: I borrowed it from Dad.
杰森∶你可以先留着,迈克,我今天晚上不会用了.
Jason: Ah, you can keep it, Mike.I won't be using it tonight.
迈克∶我是迈克西维尔.
Mike: Hi.I...I'm Mike Seaver.
柯尼∶哦,你好,我是...
Courtney: Oh?Hello, I'm...
迈克∶柯尼普雷斯顿.我是从黑猩猩广告上认识你的.
Mike: Courtney Preston.I know you from the chimp commercial.
柯尼∶哦,上帝,他们还在播放那个可怕的广告?
Courtney: Oh, God, are they still running that awful thing?
迈克∶没错.当他们停播时,我已经录下来了.
Mike: Yeah.And when they stop, I got it on tape.
柯尼:很惊喜你还能记得我,在广告都已经停播了之后.
Courtney: I'm surprised you remembered me, after all Zippy got the close-up.
迈克∶嘿,那是因为他们要剃他的毛.
Mike: Oh, hey, that's only 'cause they shaved him.
柯尼∶哦,你是一个好人..
Courtney: Oh, you're very kind.
迈克∶请坐.我要请你帮我个忙.
Mike: Oh, here have a seat.I'm gonna ask you something.
我现在正在为戏剧节日导演一个小型的场景,
See, I'm a directing this little scene for the big drama festival,
所以我想,
and I was wondering like, if you weren't in a movie or something,
如果你现在没有在拍电影或什么的话,也许你可以加入到我的场景中来.
maybe you could be in it.
柯尼∶哦,迈克,我愿意....
Courtney: Oh, Mike, I'd love to..
迈克∶太棒了!太棒了,那我明天在...
Mike: Great!Great, so I'll meet you tomorrow at...
柯尼∶但是我不能.
Courtney: ...But I can't.
迈克∶为什么?
Mike: Why?
柯尼∶今天一早,有人就请我去参加另一个场面的演出.
Courtney: I was asked to be in another scene really early this morning.
导演的名字是凯特...
The director's name is Kate Mc...
迈克∶麦克旦尼尔?凯特麦克旦尼尔!
Mike: McDonnell?Kate McDonnell!I don't believe this!
我不相信!我在掷硬币的时候光明正大的赢了你.
I won you fair and square in that coin toss.
柯尼∶你是肯尼迪?
Courtney: Are you a Kennedy?
迈克∶不是.
Mike: No.
柯尼∶没关系,对不起迈克,
Courtney: Well, it doesn't matter.
不过还是祝你的戏能拍的很好.
I'm sorry Mike, but good luck with your play anyway.
迈克∶哦,谢谢.
Mike: Oh, thanks.
柯尼∶你在做灵欲思凡的一个场景?
Courtney: You're doing a scene from Night of the Iguana?
你在做田纳西威廉!
You're doing Tennessee Williams!
迈克∶是的...
Mike: Well yeah...
柯尼∶我一直都想演威廉的剧本!
Courtney: I have been dying to do something by Williams!
迈克∶;好了,那么就加入我们吧.
Mike: Oh, great, well then do it.
柯尼∶那我怎么跟凯特说?
Courtney: But what do I tell Kate?
迈克∶告诉凯特,她是一个肮脏的,杂种的,
Mike: Tell Kate, she's a dirty, double-crossing, back-stabbing....
专会背后害人的人....就算她拥有大眼睛,美丽的头发和让人喷血的身材.
It doesn't matter if she's got great eyes, beautiful hair and a killer body.
迈克∶大家早上好!欢迎加入灵欲思凡剧组.
Mike: Morning everybody and welcome to Night of the...Iguana.
在我们开工前,我有几件事情要跟大家说.首先,
OK, before we start, I just wanna say a couple of things.
欢迎大家所有人的到来,尤其是柯尼你.
First, thank you all for coming, especially you Courtney.
柯尼∶哦,迈克.
Courtney: Oh, Mike, come on.
迈克∶大家先坐下,我们先把场景从头到尾看一遍,好吗?
Mike: Everyone have a seat and we'll read through the scene,
(在迈克的脑海中)天慢慢黑下来,我们可以听得见海浪拍打岸边的声音.这是一个安静的墨西哥夜晚,
OK?(In Mike's head) With lights down we can hear the surf.
但是,激情四射.哦,
It's a quiet evening in Mexico, but passions run deep.Oh, she is so bad.
她怎么这么差,天啊,她很差劲吗?
Man, is she bad?And she's done sit-coms!
可是她却演过情景喜剧!如果是这样的话,我岂不是可以成为ABC的一员了.
Well I be none of the ones on ABC.
柯尼∶迈克!迈克!
Courtney: Mike!Mike!That's the end of the scene.
场景拍完了,你要不要重新再来一次?
Do you wanna run it again from the top?
迈克:不.
Mike: Err...No.(In his head) One more word and I'll shoot myself.(Spoken)
(在他的脑海里)不能再说一句话了.我想第一天大家都很努力,
I think everyone's worked pretty hard for the first day,
看看明天怎么样.
so I'll see everybody tomorrow.
柯尼:你有没有要提示我的.
Courtney: Do you have any notes you want me to think about for tomorrow.
迈克∶(在他的脑海里),对,不要回来了.(说)没有,
Mike: (In his head) Yeah, don't come back.(Spoken) No, no, no,
没有,没有,我觉得很好.
I think it's going pretty good.
柯尼∶如果你有什么问题,要马上告诉我.
Courtney: 'Cause if you have concerns, don't hesitate to speak up.
迈克∶(在他的脑海里)你根本就像条死金枪鱼.(说)没有,
Mike: (In his head) You stink, like a dead mackerel.(Spoken) No,
我没有什么要说的.
I got nothing to say.
柯尼∶明天见.
Courtney: OK, see you tomorrow.
迈克∶再见(在他的脑海里)不知道能不能找到那只黑猩猩.
Mike: OK, bye bye.(In his head) I wonder if that chimp is available.
凯特∶哦,打扰一下.
Kate: Oh, excuse me.
柯尼∶哦,凯特,
Courtney: Oh, Kate, listen,
我希望迈克能向你解释不能出演你的戏,我是多么的内疚.
I hope Mike explained to you how bad I felt about not doing your scene.
凯特∶不用再想了.我一直都在隔壁房间排练,
Kate: Don't give it a thought.
一切都很棒.
I've been rehearsing in the room next door, and everything's going great.
柯尼∶那我就感觉好多了.晚安,你们2个.
Courtney: That makes me feel better.Goodnight you guys.
迈克∶晚安.凯特,我犯了一个不可原谅的错误.
Mike: Good night.Oh, Kate, I have made a terrible mistake.
凯特∶你当然是.在我把她从你的光明正大而又狡猾的人的手中把她抢过来时,
Kate: You bet you have.
你又把她从我的手中抢回去了.
You stole her from me, after I stole her from you fair and square you weasel.
迈克∶凯特,她坏透了!
Mike: Kate, she stinks!
凯特∶她什么?
Kate: She what?
迈克:她花了八个小时演,最后赢了.
Mike: She spent eight hours playing Night of the Iguana...and the Iguana won.
凯特∶你出去.
Kate: Get out of here.
迈克∶我是认真的.
Mike: I'm serious.You know,
那些来看这部戏的人一定会以为我选错了业务.
whoever comes to see this play is gonna think that I am in the wrong business.
凯特∶迈克,柯尼可是一个专业演员.
Kate: Mike, Courtney's a professional, for goodness' sake.
迈克∶我只希望田纳西威廉不要来看演出.
Mike: Well I just hope Tennessee Williams doesn't come to this production.
凯特∶迈克,他死了.
Kate: Mike, he's dead.
迈克∶那他就是个很幸运的人.
Mike: Then he's a lucky man.
凯特∶这只不过是排演的第一天而已,也许她只是克制着自己.
Kate: Look ,it's the first day of rehearsal, maybe she's just holding back.
迈克∶恩,我也希望她不会把事情搞砸了.
Mike: Yeah, well I hope she never lets it go.
凯特∶所以,她臭死了,哈?
Kate: So, she stinks, huh?
迈克:辛苦!好,
Mike: Big time!Fine, you can laugh all you want Kate,
凯特你尽管笑话我,我会解雇她.
but I've got to fire her.
凯特∶迈克,为什么她会这么坏而居然都不知道?
Kate: Mike, how can she be that bad and not know it?
迈克∶我也不知道.等等....
Mike: I don't know.Wait a minute...wait a minute, that's a great idea!
等等,真是个好主意!
OK, I'll let her do the preview performance,
对,我会让她参加预演,到时她肯定会被观众嘘下台的,
she'll get booed off the stage and she'll quit...
然后她就会退出...然后我再利用一个星期的时间找人来代替她参加最后的演出.
and then I'll have a week to replace her before the big show.
凯特∶你真没种..
Kate: Isn't that kind of gutless
迈克:是的,我应该解雇她.
Mike: Yeah, you're right, I should just fire her.
用硬币试一下?背面解雇她,正面相反.
OK, I'll tell you what I'll do; I'll flip a coin, right?
凯特,我很紧张.
Tails I fire her, heads I'm gutless.Kate, you look, I'm too nervous.
凯特∶反面.
Kate: Tails.
迈克∶什么?
Mike: What?
凯特∶不,是正面.就像另一面一样.
Kate: No, it's heads.Just like the other side.
迈克:(在他的脑海里)是的!
Mike: (In his head) Yes!Yes!She's stinking up the joint.
是的!
She's history, she'll realise and quit.
她应该退出.
She's related to all those people, that's the only explanation.
凯特:我觉得相信一个用硬币来决定的人是错误的.
Kate: I suppose I should blame myself for trusting a guy with a two-headed
coin.
迈克∶你的话是什么意思?
Mike: What are you talking about?
凯特∶哦,凯特.她很糟糕的.
Kate: Oh, Kate, she's terrible.
她演灵欲思凡,但是,鬣蜥却赢了.
She played Night of the Iguana, and the iguana won.
迈克∶什么,那你认为她很好?
Mike: What, you thought she was good?
凯特∶是.
Kate: Yes.
迈克∶这肯定是个梦.等等,
Mike: This has got to be a dream.
不可能是梦,你还穿着衣服呢.
Wait a minute, this can't be a dream, you've got all your clothes on.
凯特∶如果那个女孩在这里所做的一切让你觉得很不好的话,
Kate: If what that girl did out there tonight is your idea of terrible,
那你就不可能在舞台上有一席之地.
you have no place anywhere near a stage.
柯尼∶哦,迈克,他们喜欢它!祝贺你!
Courtney: Oh, Mike, they loved it!Congratulations!
迈克∶嗯...你有疑问吗?
Mike: Um...you had doubts?
麦琪∶哦,迈克,你会演戏,你会导演,你所有的都能做!
Maggie: Oh, Mike, you can act, you can direct, you can do it all!
杰森∶嘿,嘿,嘿!那是我的儿子!
Jason: Hey, hey, hey, hey, that's my boy!
本∶哦!哇!
Ben: Wow!
迈克∶嘿,不要告诉我你也喜欢柯尼.
Mike: Hey, don't tell me you liked Courtney too.
本∶我屁股都没动过!
Ben: My butt didn't go numb once!
迈克∶好了,妈妈,
Mike: OK, so, Mom, Dad, you can tell me;
爸爸,你们可以告诉我;你们难道不认为这里有一个主要的问题吗?
don't you think I had one major problem out there?
杰森∶我不知道.我眼里只有柯尼!
Jason: I don't know.All I could see was Courtney!
麦琪∶失陪一下,宝贝儿,我们要去祝贺她.
Maggie: Excuse us honey, we wanna go congratulate her too.
迈克∶(在他的脑海里)或许我跟舞台无缘.
Mike: (In his head) Maybe I have no business near a stage.
开萝尔∶迈克,太棒了!精彩的.
Carol: Mike, it was wonderful!Brilliant.
迈克∶开萝尔,你为何不杀了我?
Mike: Carol, why don't you just shoot me?
开萝尔∶我是说真的,我爱它,尤其是柯尼.
Carol: I mean it, I loved it, especially Courtney.
迈克:如果你没有什么难听的话要说,
Mike: Look, if you don't have anything nasty to say,
不要说了.
don't say anything at all.
开萝尔∶那你想要我说什么?
Carol: What do you want me to say?
迈克∶我要你说实话.她实在是差劲极了.
Mike: I want you to say the truth.She was terrible.
这些认为她演的好的人都是彻头彻尾的疯子!
You know, these people are absolutely nuts to think she was good!
开萝尔∶我不明白!
Carol: I don't get it!
你终于有部戏做的让我不必跟你说谎话了,
You finally do a play where I don't have to lie to you and you don't
而你却不愿意听.
wanna hear it.
迈克∶你说说谎是什么意思?
Mike: What do you mean, lie?
开萝尔∶一直以来你都表演的像一个死金枪鱼,但是,
Carol: All the times I had to tell you, you were good,
我不得不跟你说,你很棒.
and you stunk like a dead mackerel.
因为那时的你不像现在做的这么好,
And I would feel guilty about telling you that if you weren't so on top
如果我说实话的话,我会感到内疚的.
of it now.
迈克∶(在他的脑海里)哦,她说的是错的,我很好,我敢肯定自己的好就像我肯定柯尼的糟糕一样...
Mike: (In his head) Oh, she's wrong.I am good, and I'm as sure of
that as I am that Courtney was
索恩教授∶最好的作业,西维尔先生.
Professor Thorn: Best work, Mr.Seaver.
杰森∶....坏的.
Mike: ...Bad.
迈克∶我最喜爱的姐姐过的怎么样?
Mike: So, how's my favourite sister doing?
开萝尔∶迈克,你想要干嘛?
Carol: What do you want, Mike?
迈克∶呃....没什么,没什么开萝尔,
Mike: Err...Nothing, nothing Carol, just came in to talk.
只是进来和你聊聊.所以,最近在学校里怎么样?
So, how's school been going lately?
开萝尔∶迈克,自从6月份以来,我今年都没有去过学校.
Carol: I'm not in school this year, Mike.I haven't been going since June.
迈克∶哦,对,对,你找到了一份...
Mike: Oh, right, right, you got one of those...
杰森∶工作..
Carol: Job s
迈克∶说对了.
Mike: Exactly.
开萝尔∶你知道,这种姐弟间的时刻对我来说真的很特别,
Carol: You know, these brother-sister moments are really special to me,
现在滚出去!
now get out!
迈克∶呃...开萝尔,
Mike: Err...Carol, I just wanted to ask you something about...
我只是想问问你关于今天晚上戏剧结束后你跟我说的话;你的话让我想了很多.
about what you said to me after the play tonight; it got me thinking.
开萝尔∶迈克一思考,柏林墙就倒了!
Carol: The Berlin Wall crumbles!Mike thinks!
迈克∶别只顾着开玩笑了.告诉我你对作为演员的我的真正的想法.
Mike: Just hold the jokes long enough to tell me what you really think of me as an actor.
开萝尔∶哦,如果我不能使用玩笑的话,那真的会很难说清楚.
Carol: Well that's gonna be tough if I can't use jokes.
迈克∶开萝尔,
Mike: Alright Carol, it's just with you...
你告诉我说这些年来,你一直都在对我说谎.
telling me that you've been lying to me all these years.
你的话让我觉得自己....
It makes me think that I'm...
开萝尔∶不是你想像中的那么好!
Carol: Not as good as you thought!
迈克∶没错.
Mike: Yeah.
开萝尔∶也许是一无是处!
Carol: And maybe no good at all!
迈克∶没错.
Mike: Yeah.
开萝尔:你怎么知道的?布鲁呼尔先生不太赞成,太好了!
Carol: What do you know?Mr.Blowhole is having doubts...great!
迈克∶开萝尔,你能不能直接告诉我.我很坏吗?
Mike: Look, Carol, will you just tell me.Do I stink?
开萝尔∶呃....(嗅)... 是.
Carol: Err...(sniffing)...Yes.
迈克∶开萝尔,我是说作为一个演员,
Mike: As an actor...as an actor, Carol.
作为一个演员.我甚至不知道自己好不好,我也不知道什么是好的.
Come on, I don't even know if I'm good anymore, I don't even know what's good.
我是说,其他的人是怎么知道的?
I mean how does anybody know?
开萝尔∶你只是知道,比如说,当提到理解力...
Carol: You just know.For instance, when it comes to intellect...well...
迈克∶那你是怎么知道,你很好呢...
Mike: So, how do you know, you're well...
开萝尔∶很简单.我的成绩都是A.
Carol: Very simple.I got straight A's.
迈克∶哦,开萝尔,那些该死的成绩又能代表什么呢?
Mike: Oh, come on, Carol, what the heck do those grades mean now?
开萝尔∶恩...
Carol: Well...
迈克∶开萝尔,你知道在实际工作中,
Mike: Come on Carol, they mean absolutely didley in the real world;
那些根本就什么都不能代表.
you know that.
开萝尔∶我是一个有名的出版社的标点部门的经理!
Carol: Well I'm head of punctuation in a prominent publishing house!
迈克:忘掉那些该死的工作.
Mike: Ooh, saving a lot of lives there, aren't you?
Forget about the stupid grades and the pointless job.
I mean, do you have any real proof that you're good?
开萝尔∶没有.
Carol: No.
迈克∶所以,你是无足轻重的.让我们回到我的问题上.
Mike: OK, you're worthless.Let's get back to my problems.
开萝尔∶我要再吃块蛋糕.
Carol: I need another piece of cake.
迈克∶哦,好了,开萝尔,我痛苦死了.你能不能忘记你没用的生活!
Mike: Oh, come on, Carol, I'm in pain here.Would you forget about your useless life!
开萝尔:哦!!
Carol: Oh!
迈克∶等等,开萝尔,帮帮我.
Mike: Wait.Come on, Carol, help me.
开萝尔∶我不能帮助任何人,因为我是没用的人.
Carol: I can't help anybody, I'm useless.
麦琪∶开萝尔,不要在你的房间里吃东西.
Maggie: Carol, don't eat in your room.
开萝尔∶不必担心,等我走到房间的时候,我已经吃完了.
Carol: Don't worry, it will be gone before I get there.
麦琪∶迈克,怎么回事?
Maggie: Mike, what's going on?
迈克∶哦,没什么,我只是问开萝尔,怎么样才能知道自己是不是很好.
Mike: Oh, nothing, I just asked Carol, how do you know if you're good.
杰森∶这是关于什么,迈克?
Jason: What's this about, Mike?
迈克:我只是看到……
Mike: Well, OK, see it's just seeing everyone going ape chips over Courtney...
麦琪∶哦,她真的是很棒.那就是演戏.
Maggie: Oh, she was wonderful.Now that is what acting is all about.
迈克∶对,这就是让吓到我的事情.事实上,
Mike: See, that's what scares me.I mean, I thought she stunk.
我认为她演的糟透了.很显然,我根本就不知道什么是表演.
Apparently I don't have a clue as to what acting's all about.
所以,大家说说,我怎么样才知道自己好不好?
Come on guys, how do I know if I'm good?
杰森∶你挖空心思所在想的这个问题,
Jason: Well what you're wrestling with here,
事实是每个人都会问自己的问题.
is an essential question that everybody asks.
迈克∶所有人都想知道我好不好!
Mike: Everybody wants to know if I'm good!
杰森∶不,迈克,是他们自己好不好.
Jason: No, Mike; if they're good.
迈克∶哦,爸爸,
Mike: Well Dad, how does a person know if they're good?
一个人怎么样才能知道自己好不好?我是说,你怎么知道你是不是一个好记者的?
I mean, how do you know if you're a good journalist?
麦琪∶哦,迈克,
Maggie: Well Mike, I've been around.
我去过很多地方.我知道怎么样来写报道,我的简历看上去会给人以很深的印象.
And I know how to put together a story, and my resume is quite impressive.
迈克:妈妈,
Mike: Come on, Mom,
你总是抱怨工作.
you've always complained about how you've worked at a dingy paper and
但是没有得到过奖励.
a bozo TV station.I mean, you haven't even won any awards!
麦琪∶当然有!我获得了年度工作母亲奖.
Maggie: Sure I have!I've won the working mother of the year award.
迈克∶你是怎么叫它的?
Mike: What did you call it?
麦琪∶猴子奖.
Maggie: The monkey award.
迈克∶猴子奖他们也必须授给某些人.
Mike: The monkey award they had to give to somebody.
麦琪∶谢谢,迈克.
Maggie: Thanks, Mike.
杰森∶迈克,
Jason: Mike, come on,
奖项并不是唯一能证明你自己好不好的证据.
now awards aren't the only way that you know you're good.
而是你妈妈做过什么才能证明她好不好.
It's what your mom does that counts.
迈克∶哦,你一直在说,自从你独立地写作以来,你卖出了很多文章!
Mike: Oh, so you're saying that since you've been writing on your own you've sold a lot of articles!
麦琪∶一篇.
Maggie: One.
迈克∶一篇!
Mike: One!
麦琪∶但是我有很多鼓励但是没有谢谢的信.在全国范围内,
Maggie: But I have had many encouraging no thank you letters.
几家好的出版社都不愿和我合作.
Some of the finest publications in the country don't wanna work with me.
迈克∶这么说,你们也都和我一样,只是猜测.
Mike: So you guys are guessing just like I am.
杰森∶迈克,你妈妈很擅长她的工作.
Jason: Mike, your mother is good at what she does.
迈克∶爸爸,我没有问她是不是擅长她所做的工作,
Mike: Dad, I'm not asking if she's good at what she does;
我是问你怎么知道的?
I'm asking how do you know?
麦琪∶对,杰森,怎么知道的?
Maggie: Yeah, Jason, how?
杰森∶好,让我来告诉你,我可以告诉你.
Jason: OK.I'll tell you.I can tell you.It's err...as...
呃..作为...在新闻业,
Well in journalism, for instance, you have to...you look...it's like an onion.
举例来说,你不得不...它就像是一个洋葱.
It's an onion.And if you peel the layers of journalism ...
它是一个洋葱.如果你剥开新闻业的外层...
Oh, well let me use psychiatry, my profession, to illustrate the facts.
哦,还是让我用心理学,我的职业来跟大家说明事实.
In my case, if I have helped the patient, I feel terrific;
在我看来,如果我帮助不了病人,我会感觉特别难过;如果我帮住了一个病人,
if I help a patient and they come to me and say I don't need to
然后他们过来跟我说,不再需要来见我了,我会感觉很开心.
see you any more, I'm fine.
迈克:爸爸,有人告诉你你很好,你相信么?
Mike: Dad, people who are a little off tell you you're good, and you believe them?
杰森∶迈克..
Jason: Mike...
迈克∶爸爸,如果那些告诉你,
Mike: Dad, think, what if who...
他们已经痊愈了的人,只是为了不再在你这里接受治疗,
who tell you that they're cured are just cutting you loose so they can
而是想去找好的心理学家的话,你会怎么想?
find a good psychiatrist?
杰森∶我是一个好的心理学家.
Jason: I am a good psychiatrist.
迈克∶爸爸...爸爸,
Mike: Dad...Dad come on, I mean, maybe the people who keep coming back,
我是说,也许那些一直回来接受治疗的人,是你根本就帮不了的人,
you're not helping and the one's who tell you they're cured are really
而那些据说已经痊愈的人,真正的目的只是去找一个可以让他们痊愈的人.
trying to find somebody who can.
杰森∶难道只因为我被哈里医生和斯特瑞兰德医生挖走了2个病人,就意味着....
Jason: Just because I lose two patients to Doctor Harry the hot tub Strickland, does not mean...
迈克∶爸爸,我不是有意要冒犯你.
Mike: Dad, I didn't mean to upset you.
杰森∶好了,行了.我可以告诉你的是,迈克,解铃还需系铃人,只有问自己这个问题的人才能回答自己的这个问题.
Jason: Oh, OK, alright, I can tell you this, Mike; that only somebody who has
ever asked himself that question has any chance of answering it
迈克:好.
Mike: Yeah.I just wish there was a way for a person to tell if he
我只是想知道怎么知道一个人是不是好.
was really good.
麦琪∶如果你找到了,告诉我一声.
Maggie: If you find it, let me know.
迈克∶我不属于这里.
Mike: I don't belong here.
索恩教授∶你现在属于.
Professor Thorn: Not at this hour, you don't.
迈克∶啊...索恩教授.你在这里做什么 ?
Mike: Ah...Professor Thorn.What are you doing here?
索恩教授∶我有头带.那你为什么会在这里?
Professor Thorn: I have tenia.What's your excuse?
迈克∶我是擅自进来的.我可以问你一些事情吗?
Mike: I'm trespassing.Can I ask you something?
索恩教授∶什么?
Professor Thorn: What?
迈克∶你怎样知道自己好不好?
Mike: How do you know if you're good?
索恩教授∶我怎么知道我自己好不好,你怎么知道你自己好不好,
Professor Thorn: How do I know I'm good,
还是一个人是怎么知道自己好不好的?
how do you know you're good or how does one know one's good?
迈克∶你最后说的那种.
Mike: The last thing you said.
索恩教授∶啊,生命的必问问题之一.
Professor Thorn: Ah, one of life's essential questions.
迈克∶啊,你的话和我爸爸说的是一样的.
Mike: Ah, you sound just like my dad.
索恩教授∶你爸爸是英国人!
Professor Thorn: Your father's British!
迈克∶不是,不是.
Mike: No.no, no, no.Acting's weird, you know?I mean, it's not like...
表演是很不可思议的,你知道吗?它不像...
like being a tight-rope walker, where...
像走钢丝的人一样,只要你没死就能证明自己是很出色的.
where you know you're good if you don't die.
索恩教授∶相信我,在演戏过程中,也可能会死掉的.
Professor Thorn: You can die in the theatre, believe me.
迈克∶教授,我是很认真的.
Mike: Come on Professor, I'm being serious.
我是说,
I mean, if you're an actor,
如果你是一个演员,你怎么知道自己是否有资格站在舞台上?
how do you know if you even have the right to be on the stage?
索恩教授:告诉我,
Professor Thorn: Are you telling me, Mr.
西维尔,
Seaver, that you have doubts about your abilities, hmm?
你怀疑自己的能力么?
You always struck me as being impervious to introspection.
迈克∶如同什么?
Mike: As what?
索恩教授∶如同一个自大的纨绔子弟.
Professor Thorn: As a confident dude.
迈克∶哦,哦,恩,直到今晚,我才有所改变.
Mike: Oh, oh, well I was...up till tonight.
索恩教授∶西维尔先生,
Professor Thorn: Mr.Seaver, as I told you,
如同我告诉过你的,
your scene was the best of the evening;
你的场景是晚会上最好的的;它显示出了你对戏剧的超凡的理解力.
it showed you had an excellent grasp on what good theatre is.
迈克∶恩,这就是问题,因为我认为它糟糕透了.
Mike: Well, see, that's the problem, because I thought it stunk.
教授∶你真的这样认为!
Professor Thorn: You did!
迈克∶完全地.
Mike: Completely.
索恩教授∶你认为这个场景糟糕透了,
Professor Thorn: And here I am jealous of you...
所以我很羡慕你,羡慕你在你的年龄阶段所达到的境界,
of what you've accomplished at your age, of what the future holds for you,
羡慕你无限宽广的未来.
and you thought the scene stunk.
迈克∶等等,你怎么可以嫉妒我呢,你是老师来着.
Mike: w...w...wait a minute, how could you be jealous of me, you're the teacher.
索恩教授∶30年前的我就像现在的你一样,我假定我是.一个年轻的,
Professor Thorn: Yeah, but thirty years ago, I was you...
才华横溢的人,准备去闯荡世界.
or at least I presumed I was.A young talented buck, ready to lick the world.
但是我没去,所以,我来了这里.
I didn't, I'm here.
迈克∶这样说来,你根本不喜欢去教戏剧.
Mike: So your saying you don't like teaching drama.
索恩教授∶不,请别误解我.我爱教戏剧.
Professor Thorn: No, don't get me wrong.I love it.
有多少人能靠做着自己喜欢的事情来谋生呢,但是,如果我有另外一次机会的话,
And how many people can make a living by doing what they really love,
我会...重点在于,你还有机会.
but if I had another chance I'd...The point is, you have that chance.
迈克∶是,但是我怎么样才能知道我自己好不好呢.
Mike: Yeah, but how do I know if I'm good.
索恩教授∶迈克,这个问题的答案根本就不像你想象的那么神秘.
Professor Thorn: Mike, the answer is not nearly so mystical as you imagine.
迈克∶不是吗?
Mike: It's not?
索恩教授∶倾听那些不得不告诉你的人的意见.
Professor Thorn: Listen to what people have to tell you.
而窍门在于要懂得去选择性的听取.我的意思是说,
But the trick is to be selective in the people you choose to listen to.
选择你尊敬的人和有品位的人的意见去听.
I mean, choose people you respect, people of taste.
迈克∶比如批评家.
Mike: You mean, like critics.
索恩教授∶我是认真的,西维尔先生.
Professor Thorn: I'm being serious Mr.Seaver.
迈克∶那么,我怎么知道该听谁的呢?
Mike: Well then, how do I know who to listen to?
索恩教授∶多年前,我出演了约瑟帕普制作的第十二晚上里的一个小角色.
Professor Thorn: Years ago,
在那之后,
I had a small part in a Joseph Pap production of Twelfth Night.
我亲爱的和蔼的母亲对我大加赞赏,
Afterwards my dear sweet mother gushed all over me and told me I was
并告诉我,我很棒...
wonderful.
迈克∶你相信了!
Mike: And you believed it!
索恩教授:当然不会.但是不管怎样,约瑟帕普先生在那场演出后和我谈话了.
Professor Thorn: Certainly not.Daffy old bat.But I digress.Anyway, Mr.
现在他不需要和我说话,但是他希望和我谈话.他说,
Pap himself spoke to me after a matinee.
年轻人,你已经实现了你的承诺.
Now he didn't have to speak to me, but he chose to.
现在,我也相信,西维尔先生.
He said, young man, you have promise.Now that Mr.Seaver I believed.
迈克∶索恩教授.
Mike: Professor Thorn.
索恩教授∶是.
Professor Thorn: Yes.
迈克∶我对这个有一点点的擅长吗?
Mike: Am I any good at this?
索恩教授∶西维尔先生,我会说...你有潜力.
Professor Thorn: Well Mr.Seaver, I'll say this...you have promise.
杰森∶耶!
Mike: Yeah!
索恩教授∶是.
Professor Thorn: Yeah.
迈克∶我真的有吗?
Mike: I do, don't I?
索恩教授∶我相信我刚才已经说过了.
Professor Thorn: I believe I just said that.
迈克∶谢谢.
Mike: Thanks.
索恩教授:西维尔,你觉得我是一个好老师么?
Professor Thorn: Mr.Seaver...do you think I'm any good, as a teacher?
迈克∶你在问我吗?
Mike: You're asking me?
索恩教授∶是.
Professor Thorn: Yes.
迈克∶我会说...你有潜力.
Mike: Well I'll say this...you have promise. Professor Thorn: Thank you Mr.
索恩教授:谢谢你,西维尔.生活是一个大舞台,
Seaver.All the world's a stage and all the men and women merely players.
每个人都是演员.他们都有自己出场的时间,可能同时扮演很多角色.
They have their exits and their entrances and one man in his time plays
00:21:35,200
many parts.